All right, you're done. Let's take a look
at the solution. Delete is actually pretty straight forward.
Note that once again we have almost useless
parameters. S actually refers to our selection while our
strings here are actually our selection Rs. One
little trickiness in delete is that if you actually
put no selection in, it'll delete all the rows.
I still want to make sure we notify the change.
I've done the slide optimization here. It would be
fine to just notify the change always, but I've decided
if no rows have been deleted, then we should
bother not notifying. Unless the selection is null, in which
case we deleted all the rows, but again, it
would be fine just to use notify change here even
if no rows are actually deleted. After all, the intention
was that rows would be deleted. Once again, let's take
pity on someone who might have to maintain your code, and change
these default parameter names to something
more useful like selection and selectionargs.
Other than that, update looks almost exactly like delete. Once
again, we are returning the number of rows impacted by
the update, and we don't bother notifying if no rows
were impacted. Now that we've finished writing update and delete, we
can go back to test provider and add some tests.
First, let's remove test delete.db, the last test that doesn't depend
on the provider. Instead, let's have a test that deletes
all the records and checks to make sure they're actually deleted.
Remember, passing a null query actually deletes all of the
records in a table. So this is really straight-forward, just passing
nulls. Since we're depending on the database for our deletes, it's
not all that particularly important that we actually test the delete
functions, although it would be nice to add that later on.
The reason we'd want to add it is to make sure that
our constraints are valid. And once we're done doing the deletes,
we check to make sure that there are no rows left.
Note that we have to delete weather entry before we delete location
entry, because you've got constraints in the database that prevent weather entry
from existing if location entries do not also exist and would also
prevent the deletion of those entries. So let's check to see whether
that actually works. All right, that passes. Good news. Now we can
add the same test to the end to make sure we can
delete all of the rows at the end and it still works.
And as you can see, they still pass. So now we know we've
deleted records before and after running tests. Now, let's try
that update. We'll do just an update of the location.
Again, let's start by deleting all records and inserting a
record that we want to update. One of the nice things about
content values is you can actually copy them using a
copy constructor. After that, we can add the ID we
want to update and then put the name of the city
we want to update it to. In this case, from North Pole
to Santa's Village. And then, finally, we call update.
Assert that we've actually updated exactly one record as
we'd expect, and then do a query on that,
validating our cursor, making sure that our update actually works.
And then finally, we close our cursor. It all
looks pretty good. And let's see that it actually runs,
and does the right thing. And our tests pass.
So, we've now proved that we can update, delete, insert,
and query and all this is fully tested.
In other words, the bones of our application
are finished, just waiting to attach our UI.
Let's go through and attach some of our UI.